<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Application Craft</title>
  <subtitle>A Blog written by Application Craft - the Visual IDE people</subtitle>
  <id>http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2012-11-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Application Craft</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Chrome Users Around the World Rejoice!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2012/11/chrome-users-around-the-world-rejoice/"/>
    <id>/blog/2012/11/chrome-users-around-the-world-rejoice/</id>
    <published>2012-11-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-11-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ahoy everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the many website changes we’ve been working hard at improving, such as fixing video links and cleaning up our &lt;a title="Application Craft Documentation blog" href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog/2012/11/documentation-search-and-full-screen/"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;, we went ahead and added in another something extra to make your life easier. &lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ahoy everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the many website changes we’ve been working hard at improving, such as fixing video links and cleaning up our &lt;a title="Application Craft Documentation blog" href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog/2012/11/documentation-search-and-full-screen/"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;, we went ahead and added in another something extra to make your life easier. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your time’s valuable! We know that and you know that, which is why we have created an app so you can access Application Craft directly from Chrome. This 2-step process will save you time to do more important things... such as creating applications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go on the &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/application-craft/fnbfgfpielckjhdohmkacklnnjkdpkdc/"&gt;Chrome Web Store&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click on the ‘Add to Chrome’ tab. This will allow you to bypass signing in via the website, as having the Chrome app will have you on your way to smooth sailing directly to your personal console. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Add to Chrome" src="/img/blog/1addchrome-df91bbda.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ta da! Now the app will appear on your Chrome homepage. All done, told you it was easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AC in Chrome" src="/img/blog/2acapp-4dbd44bf.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With over 100 users using the Chrome app we invite you to jump on board to join the other happy crafters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any questions? Just &lt;a href="mailto:support@applicationcraft.com"&gt;give us a holler&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ta ta for now,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hazel&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My First App - the first of many Tutorials</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2012/11/my-first-app-tutorial/"/>
    <id>/blog/2012/11/my-first-app-tutorial/</id>
    <published>2012-11-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-11-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Crimes &amp;amp; Misdemeanours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess all companies commit them. Well we are now atoning for a pretty major crime - not having a really good &amp;#39;Getting Started&amp;#39; guide so that first time users can go from zero to hero in a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_1"&gt;&lt;a href="/developers/documentation/my-first-app/"&gt;Click here to see it live &amp;raquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Crimes &amp;amp; Misdemeanours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess all companies commit them. Well we are now atoning for a pretty major crime - not having a really good &amp;#39;Getting Started&amp;#39; guide so that first time users can go from zero to hero in a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_1"&gt;&lt;a href="/developers/documentation/my-first-app/"&gt;Click here to see it live &amp;raquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we released our new web site, Joel also built a new framework for our all our documentation. We just finished all the major tweaks and so we are now using it for a complete set of tutorials, My First App being the first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;8 Steps, 15 Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 8 easy steps and about 15 minutes of work, you get to build and deploy an App but you really get to play with most of the major components of Application Craft, including&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;designing a very simple UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;changing properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;writing some code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Coming soon ...&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My First App is the first part of some major tutorial work. The main ones we are about to start work on are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a complete set of &lt;strong&gt;Javascript for Beginners&lt;/strong&gt; tutorials that use Application Craft as a great way to learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a comprehensive collection of &lt;strong&gt;Application Craft By Example&lt;/strong&gt; tutorials, which will conentrate on getting into the really meaty aspects of using the product with lots of detailed examples. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;Feedback Please!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please add your commments to this blog. We really do take notice so any ideas, suggestions, typo spots (etc.) are much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Introducing A New Way to Talk</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2012/11/a-new-way-to-talk/"/>
    <id>/blog/2012/11/a-new-way-to-talk/</id>
    <published>2012-11-28T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-11-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve added a really easy way for you to contact us through your account using &lt;a title="Intercom" href="https://www.intercom.io/"&gt;Intercom.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Login to your account and look for the mail icon to the left of your username in the main console area and also in the design area at the top right of the browser. Click it, and you will have access to your AC Inbox, which you can use to quickly send a message to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve added a really easy way for you to contact us through your account using &lt;a title="Intercom" href="https://www.intercom.io/"&gt;Intercom.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Login to your account and look for the mail icon to the left of your username in the main console area and also in the design area at the top right of the browser. Click it, and you will have access to your AC Inbox, which you can use to quickly send a message to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s easy to use and allows you quick and easy access to all messages you have sent or received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply click the icon, compose your message and send.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Send Message" alt="Send" src="/img/blog/newmessagesend-7efa0f0c.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its as easy as that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also view your conversations summary clicking here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="View Summary" alt="View Summary" src="/img/blog/viewmessage-301d7eea.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and from there you can then select a conversation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="View Conversations" alt="View Conversation" src="/img/blog/viewconversations-aa328c42.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to see the conversation detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Conversation Detail" alt="View Detail" src="/img/blog/conversationdetail-f02acbe3.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will also be using this to let you know about new features or news, so watch out for this. We&amp;#39;d love to know what you think so please let us know and we look forward to talking to you sometime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ian&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Documentation Improvements: Search and Full Screen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2012/11/documentation-search-and-full-screen/"/>
    <id>/blog/2012/11/documentation-search-and-full-screen/</id>
    <published>2012-11-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every since we unleashed our &lt;a href="/blog/2012/11/welcome-to-the-all-new-application-craft/"&gt;new site and branding&lt;/a&gt; to the world just a week ago, we&amp;#39;ve been hard at work making further improvements, especially to the &lt;a href="/developers/documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;. Today, we added a couple of major improvements to the docs that we hope will make your life easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every since we unleashed our &lt;a href="/blog/2012/11/welcome-to-the-all-new-application-craft/"&gt;new site and branding&lt;/a&gt; to the world just a week ago, we&amp;#39;ve been hard at work making further improvements, especially to the &lt;a href="/developers/documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;. Today, we added a couple of major improvements to the docs that we hope will make your life easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Docs Search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old docs had a search feature, which it seems that some of you have been pining for. So we&amp;#39;ve brought search back, but in a much sexier way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above the documentation tree, you will now see a search box. Simply use this to search for what you are looking for and you&amp;#39;ll be shown a list of results from the documentation. Nice and fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Documentation search results" src="/img/blog/doc-search-f202a141.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Full Screen Docs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also have noticed a little icon towards the top right of the docs. If you click that, you will be taken into full-screen mode, which will allow you to concentrate only on the docs without any distractions, and also be able to see more of the docs and code samples with much less scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Full-Screen Documentation" src="/img/blog/full-screen-docs-f803200a.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Open Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I sent a tweet from the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/appcrafty"&gt;@appcrafty&lt;/a&gt; Twitter account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We think our new site and docs are so good, we open sourced them &lt;a href="https://t.co/ONYMrozB" title="https://github.com/ApplicationCraft/applicationcraft.com"&gt;github.com/ApplicationCra…&lt;/a&gt;, and we would love to see pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Application Craft (@appcrafty) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/appcrafty/status/271365264317235200" data-datetime="2012-11-21T21:31:35+00:00"&gt;November 21, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything that you see here and anywhere else on our site is now open source on &lt;a href="https://github.com/ApplicationCraft/applicationcraft.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. Which means the code behind the site and documentation is open and available for anyone to view... yes even you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you see a typo, or broken link; or if a page in the docs is not looking quite right; or maybe there is a page in that you think you can improve upon, then just go ahead and &lt;a href="https://github.com/ApplicationCraft/applicationcraft.com"&gt;fork the site&lt;/a&gt;, make your changes and send us a &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/using-pull-requests"&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;. If all looks good, we&amp;#39;ll have no problem with accepting your pull requests, and you will see your changes on our site the next time we deploy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty more to come, so watch this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome to the all New ApplicationCraft</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2012/11/welcome-to-the-all-new-application-craft/"/>
    <id>/blog/2012/11/welcome-to-the-all-new-application-craft/</id>
    <published>2012-11-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Unless you are reading this via the &lt;a href="/blog/feed.xml"&gt;blog feed&lt;/a&gt;, you are currently witnessing the beauty and majesty that is the all new &lt;a href="/"&gt;ApplicationCraft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve been hard at work for the last month thinking and brainstorming about ways we can create an even better product and improve the service to you; our valued customers and developers. The site is the very first thing that people see, and is also the go-to place for existing users when they need assistance of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Unless you are reading this via the &lt;a href="/blog/feed.xml"&gt;blog feed&lt;/a&gt;, you are currently witnessing the beauty and majesty that is the all new &lt;a href="/"&gt;ApplicationCraft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve been hard at work for the last month thinking and brainstorming about ways we can create an even better product and improve the service to you; our valued customers and developers. The site is the very first thing that people see, and is also the go-to place for existing users when they need assistance of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what we have done is completely redefined the Application Craft brand and design. We enlisted the help of &lt;a href="http://mikekus.com/"&gt;Mike Kus&lt;/a&gt;, who is one of the worlds best web and graphic designers - and also happens to be a great guy - and we built a beautiful new brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brief was simple; great looking site that was far simpler and less text heavy than the old one, and we wanted it to be instantly noticable and funky!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Mike came up with blew us away. It includes an all new logo that we feel is much simpler, yet more effective, and the site does a far better job of explaining very quickly what AC is all about. We even invented a new colour: AC Red ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="/"&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt; gets straight to the point, and our &lt;a href="/product"&gt;product pages&lt;/a&gt; are much simpler. Heck, even the &lt;a href="/get-started"&gt;signup form&lt;/a&gt; is simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also found the time to integrate the &lt;a href="/developers/documentation"&gt;User Guide and documentation&lt;/a&gt; into the new site, as well as make some considerable improvements to the structure and useability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are very excited to release the new ApplicationCraft.com, and hope you will love it as much as we do. Tell us what you think in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AC Mobile Build, a PhoneGap Build alternative with Plugins</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2012/11/ac-mobile-build/"/>
    <id>/blog/2012/11/ac-mobile-build/</id>
    <published>2012-11-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-11-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re really excited to announce the availability of a full-featured alternative to PhoneGap Build that incorporates everything that Adobe&amp;#39;s platform offers as well as a healthy number of plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to take a look at the &lt;a href="/developers/documentation/ac-mobile-build-phonegap/ac-mobile-build/external-html5cssjs-apps"&gt;User Guide section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re really excited to announce the availability of a full-featured alternative to PhoneGap Build that incorporates everything that Adobe&amp;#39;s platform offers as well as a healthy number of plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to take a look at the &lt;a href="/developers/documentation/ac-mobile-build-phonegap/ac-mobile-build/external-html5cssjs-apps"&gt;User Guide section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don&amp;#39;t know PhoneGap/Cordova, it lets you take any HTML5+CSS+JS App or Site and compile it into a binary that can be deployed to App Stores. It also lets you access all the hardware goodies on your device (GPS, Accelerometer, Compass, Camera etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve also made it incredibly easy to use by offering Certificate management &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; Certificate generation, as well as config.xml editing - all through the Application Craft platform. So, no problem even if you don&amp;#39;t have a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;#39;t matter what tools you used to build your App, any HTML5+CSS+JS App should work just fine. And for you Application Craft developers, all you need to know is that it is very easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Application Craft Mobile Build" alt="AC Mobile Build" src="/img/blog/acmb-2-dcb1aaf7.png" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Why we built it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PhoneGap/Cordova technology is something that most developers are probably already familiar with. However, using it is not for the faint hearted. You need to install and configure XCode (for iOS), Java (for Android and Blackberry) and other compilers. This is a pain in the arse and it is why PhoneGap:Build was built. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we make pretty heavy use of PhoneGap/Cordova, we needed to be in a position where we have control over the build process. Being able to add plugins in line with our users&amp;#39;s needs was on e pretty key motivator to build our own platform. The other was the simple need to be in control and not end up red-faced because of changes that Adobe might make. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would, at this point, like to say thanks to the PhoneGap crew - especially Brian &amp;quot;Spacelord&amp;quot; Leroux and Andrew &amp;quot;Sorry for the Snark&amp;quot; Lunny, who have been especially helpful to us in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;How does it differ from PhoneGap:Build?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In principle, it is very similar. The main differences are free private builds, 6 PhoneGap/Cordova plugins, being able to edit your config.xml without re-uploading and keeping a a history of compiled Apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application Craft will only support iOS, Android (both available now) and Windows Phone (available from December 1st, 2012). We simply don&amp;#39;t see the need for Blackberry, Symbian and WebOS I&amp;#39;m afraid. You can still use PhoneGap:Build for those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Plugins?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application Craft curates plugins. This means that they are built and tested by us to reduce complexity for the user. We have added the most commonly requested ones but will aggressively add more in line with demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Child Browser Window&lt;/strong&gt; : this allows a user to display a URL within the app rather than it appearing in the system browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Push Notifications&lt;/strong&gt; : we have integrated the Xtify system and may support others on request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scandit Barcode Reader&lt;/strong&gt; : a very high quality barcode reader; it is requires a commcercial license but for mission critical barcode reading it is worth it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google ZXing&lt;/strong&gt; : this is a free barcode reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SQLite&lt;/strong&gt; : this gives you a relational database on your mobile device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MailTo&lt;/strong&gt; : send emails from your device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want more? We build plugins based on popular demand. If plenty of people want one, we&amp;#39;ll add it. If you have a very obscure plugin you want adding, our services guys can look at that, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
