<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Application Craft</title>
  <subtitle>A Blog written by Application Craft - the Visual IDE people</subtitle>
  <id>http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Application Craft</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Quick and Easy Database CRUD with Parse</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/01/quick-and-easy-database-crud-with-parse/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/01/quick-and-easy-database-crud-with-parse/</id>
    <published>2013-01-14T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over Christmas we introduced the easiest yet way for you to to create, read, update and delete data in any AC application. We partnered up with &lt;a href="http://parse.com"&gt;Parse&lt;/a&gt; to provide an extremely low barrier to entry data backend using their &lt;a href="https://parse.com/docs/rest#objects"&gt;Objects API&lt;/a&gt;. Making the whole &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt; process amazingly easy to implement into any app.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over Christmas we introduced the easiest yet way for you to to create, read, update and delete data in any AC application. We partnered up with &lt;a href="http://parse.com"&gt;Parse&lt;/a&gt; to provide an extremely low barrier to entry data backend using their &lt;a href="https://parse.com/docs/rest#objects"&gt;Objects API&lt;/a&gt;. Making the whole &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt; process amazingly easy to implement into any app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;#39;t go into too much detail here as the &lt;a href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/developers/documentation/product-guide/advanced-features/parse/objects/"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; already does that well. So instead I will prove to you you just how easy it is to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Available Methods&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have created a new &lt;code&gt;parse.objects&lt;/code&gt; class which your app has access to. This new class contains 5 methods which cover everything you need to create, read, update and delete data, as well as a powerful querying API:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/developers/documentation/scripting-apis/server-side-api/parse-object/objectcreate"&gt;parse.objects.create()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/developers/documentation/scripting-apis/server-side-api/parse-object/objectread"&gt;parse.objects.read()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/developers/documentation/scripting-apis/server-side-api/parse-object/objectupdate"&gt;parse.objects.update()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/developers/documentation/scripting-apis/server-side-api/parse-object/objectdelete"&gt;parse.objects.delete()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/developers/documentation/scripting-apis/server-side-api/parse-object/objectquery"&gt;parse.objects.query()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Example Scenario&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to keep a record of my book collection, including details of each book. So lets start by creating an object (or record) for each book in my collection (I only have one right now):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;parse.objects.create(&amp;#39;books&amp;#39;, {
  title: &amp;#39;The Lord of the Rings&amp;#39;,
  author: &amp;#39;JRR Tolkien&amp;#39;
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will return a Javascript object containing the &lt;code&gt;objectId&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;createdAt&lt;/code&gt; date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  objectId: &amp;quot;DM5XhFTiPR&amp;quot;,
  createdAt: &amp;quot;2013-01-14T11:41:24.174Z&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forgot to add the publication date, so let&amp;#39;s update my record:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;parse.objects.update(&amp;#39;books&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;DM5XhFTiPR&amp;#39;, {
  publishedAt: &amp;quot;1954-07-21T00:00:00.000Z&amp;quot;
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s take a look at our updated object using the &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;parse.objects.read(&amp;#39;books&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;DM5XhFTiPR&amp;#39;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our object now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  title: &amp;#39;The Lord of the Rings&amp;#39;,
  author: &amp;#39;JRR Tolkien&amp;#39;,
  publishedAt: &amp;#39;1954-07-21T00:00:00.000Z&amp;#39;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that my wife just threw away my book, so I now need to delete this object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;parse.objects.delete(&amp;#39;books&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;DM5XhFTiPR&amp;#39;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But being a good wife that she is, she bought me a shiny new replacement, along with a few others for me to read. So I created a new record for each of my new books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now have quite a few books in collection, but want to find only those written by JRR Tolkien:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;parse.objects.query(&amp;#39;books&amp;#39;, {
  where: {
    author: &amp;#39;JRR Tolkien&amp;#39;
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above will return me a &lt;code&gt;results&lt;/code&gt; array, containing all objects which have an author of &amp;#39;JRR Tolkien&amp;#39;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the basics, and there is of course a lot more that you can do, including some pretty advanced querying. But you should be able to see from the above how quick and easy it is to use the new Parse powered database support in Application Craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/developers/documentation/product-guide/advanced-features/parse/"&gt;Check out the docs&lt;/a&gt; for more, and leave your comments below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Push Notification app in minutes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/01/push-notifications/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/01/push-notifications/</id>
    <published>2013-01-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-01-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have just completed full support for Push Notifications in Application Craft, and have teamed up with &lt;a href="http://www.xtify.com"&gt;Xtify&lt;/a&gt;, who provide the underlying push technology. You will need to create an Account with them, although this is free (you start paying Xtify once you reach large volumes).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have just completed full support for Push Notifications in Application Craft, and have teamed up with &lt;a href="http://www.xtify.com"&gt;Xtify&lt;/a&gt;, who provide the underlying push technology. You will need to create an Account with them, although this is free (you start paying Xtify once you reach large volumes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also added a new drop-in API that makes it ridiculously easy to add support for push notifications in your app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How easy? Well this is all it takes ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You create an App in Application Craft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You create an App in Xtify for &lt;a href="/developers/documentation/ac-mobile-build-phonegap/ac-mobile-build/ac-build-plugins/xtify-push-notifications/configuration/iOS/xtify-ios-portal-setup/"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt; or for &lt;a href="/developers/documentation/ac-mobile-build-phonegap/ac-mobile-build/ac-build-plugins/xtify-push-notifications/configuration/android/xtify-android-portal-setup/"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You generate your iOS / Android keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You add the following code to your App&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;function notificationReceived() {
    // Your own, optional callback function
    // Called when your App receives the notification
}

function handler_application_onAppStarted(){
    xtify.applicationKeyiOS = &amp;quot;12345678-9754-4ffc-be65-ecd00a482269&amp;quot;;
    xtify.applicationKeyAndroid = &amp;quot;abcdefg-9754-4ffc-be65-ecd00a482269&amp;quot;;
    xtify.startedCallback = notificationReceived;
    xtify.init();
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You send out the Notification from &lt;a href="/developers/documentation/ac-mobile-build-phonegap/ac-mobile-build/ac-build-plugins/xtify-push-notifications/xtify-push-message/"&gt;Xtify&lt;/a&gt;, or from your own App using &lt;a href="/developers/documentation/ac-mobile-build-phonegap/ac-mobile-build/ac-build-plugins/xtify-push-notifications/apis/xtify-notification-api/"&gt;our API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;The AC Xtify API&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have added our own API that sits in front of the Xtify system and makes life really very easy for you. However, you can always access the Xtify API directly if required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main features of this are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ease-of-use is at the top of the list; less experienced developers may struggle with Xtify&amp;#39;s own API and so we have simplified things for all common operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allows you to operate in test mode, so you can test lots of things from your desktop rather than a mobile device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a single call &amp;#39;xtify.location.update()&amp;#39; that automatically tells the Xtify system where the user is located. You can then set up auto notifications based on a user&amp;#39;s location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a cool &amp;#39;Tag API&amp;#39; that lets your App tag users with any information you require, typically information gathered from the App itself. You can then send out notifications only to those users with certain tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>GjiGan - Your City at your Fingertips</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/01/gjigan/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/01/gjigan/</id>
    <published>2013-01-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-01-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sylvain Danigo has come up with an app using Application Craft that will transform the way citizens can interact with the Canadian town of Blainville. The mobile app, named &lt;a href="http://www.gjigan.com/"&gt;GjiGan&lt;/a&gt; (pronounced Jee-Gan), provides smartphone users both commercial and municipal information in real time. We had a chance to speak with Sylvain about the creation of GjiGan&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sylvain Danigo has come up with an app using Application Craft that will transform the way citizens can interact with the Canadian town of Blainville. The mobile app, named &lt;a href="http://www.gjigan.com/"&gt;GjiGan&lt;/a&gt; (pronounced Jee-Gan), provides smartphone users both commercial and municipal information in real time. We had a chance to speak with Sylvain about the creation of GjiGan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_0"&gt;Tell us more about GjiGan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GjiGan is more than just a simple directory. The application presents news in real time, whether it’s municipal information, promotions, offers from local merchants, and even job listings. The application can be customized according to the type of information selected and your interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app extracts news from the town’s official website so only the current and official news appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_1"&gt;Sounds great! What has the user response been like?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are over 600 users (the app was launched last month). Citizens like it because it’s a free app and gives them the town’s current information and includes interesting features, such as interactive maps. Businesses like it because it gives them a chance to promote and advertise on the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_2"&gt;Why did you choose Application Craft?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make mobile apps a year ago and looked at various platforms. The first thing that pulled me towards Application Craft was the fact that it is cloud-based. It’s easy to build screens and works immediately on mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_3"&gt;What was your favourite aspect of Application Craft?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the drag and drop. I found it easy to quickly build what I wanted. Had I chosen a different platform it would have taken me twice the amount of time, definitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the widgets easy to program, enjoyed the many functionalities Application Craft has to offer and think Application Craft is very good value for what it offers and what I’ve been able to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make things even better, I found the support great! The forum was a good place to ask questions and I received answers very quickly, either by the Application Craft staff or from other people on the forum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_4"&gt;Any future Application Craft plans?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, I have another project lined up and have many customers asking for mobile development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="toc_5"&gt;One last question... How did you come up with GjiGan’s name?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gjigan” means village in the Micmac* language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full case study can be found &lt;a href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/pdf/testimonials/AC%20Case%20Study%20GjiGan.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Here’s a little Canadian history lesson for you: Micmacs are a First Nations people, located in Canada’s Maritime Provinces and the Gaspé Peninsula of Quebec, as well as some parts of New England, USA. “Micmac” both refers to the people themselves and the language they speak. The Micmac were among the first peoples to be affected by European activities in the New World and underwent early depopulation and sociocultural disruption. Quick lesson over!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CSS Styling in Application Craft</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/01/css-styling/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/01/css-styling/</id>
    <published>2013-01-07T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-01-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Introducing Manos Koufakis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manos has been an Application Craft user since we were in beta last year. His first app made it to #2 in the Apple App Store, beating eBay, Skype and other household names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manos has produced a great new app (currently pre-release) that makes heavy use of CSS Styling and we thought it would be great to share his experiences with you. Manos has provided ...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Introducing Manos Koufakis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manos has been an Application Craft user since we were in beta last year. His first app made it to #2 in the Apple App Store, beating eBay, Skype and other household names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manos has produced a great new app (currently pre-release) that makes heavy use of CSS Styling and we thought it would be great to share his experiences with you. Manos has provided ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href="http://acft.ws/nsnd"&gt;working app&lt;/a&gt; that you can run in your desktop browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/9bJSG-ETZvs?autoplay=1&amp;hd=1&amp;fs=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;rel=0&amp;" class="fancybox fancybox.iframe"&gt; Video Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; of how he did this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a list of useful resources (below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Style like a pro with Application Craft&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started using Application Craft (nearly 1 year ago), I was really excited with the Widget drag and drop environment that allowed for really speedy development without having to care about containers, specifying complex div structure etc. So I made my first app with AC, named Βρες Δώρο (Find Gift), that does what its title indicates - it helps you find a gift for any circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without using ANY custom CSS style, relying only on the provided AC themes and widgets I completed my app and it rocketed to the #2 position in the App store and stayed there for nearly 1 week! I was really blown away! The application received triumphant comments, but what  started bothering me, was that there were a few comments referring to poor design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meanwhile, I started developing my second app called “Find the Movie”, which is a movie quiz game where the user is called to guess a film by looking at a screenshot. For that app I co-operated with a graphic arts company in order to have cool icons and design in my app and avoid any negative criticism. When the art project completed, I was provided with a set of .psd files and NO CSS. That was a nightmare for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the hell can I implement all those fancy gradients, cool button icons etc. into AC? AC is a widget based platform and there is NO theme roller. Plus, I really hate messing with CSS! As much as I like programming, my head aches when I have to deal with CSS styling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the initial panic, I searched a bit on the AC forum and read a bit about the &lt;a href="https://getsatisfaction.com/application_craft/topics/application_craft_custom_css_classes_how_do_i_reference_these_with_a_url"&gt;Custom CSS Properties&lt;/a&gt; that you can see as an option to every widget you see.&lt;br&gt;
That was the key to paradise!  I started writing my own CSS styles and in a short period of time, I transformed a poorly looking app to a really nice looking quiz game. You can see the result here and play around with the pre-release demo:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://acft.ws/nsnd"&gt;http://acft.ws/nsnd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;OK, so much for the talk, now how do you do it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to transform your application and implement your custom styles, you will need 4 tools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.w3schools.com/"&gt;http://www.w3schools.com/&lt;/a&gt; - even if you think you’re a CSS expert, it’s nearly impossible to remember by heart all these great features of CSS and CSS3, so you can use that website as a reference in case you forget something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Chrome or Firefox debugger (or any debugger that you like) – myself I’ve been using mostly the &lt;a href="http://developer.chrome.com/extensions/debugger.html"&gt;Chrome debugger&lt;/a&gt;, ‘cause I like Chrome best. This is the most useful tool in order to know what to do. So every time you want to style a certain page, you open the page, then open the debugger and with the use of the Element Inspector (that little magnifying glass at the bottom) you can click any element on your page and you are provided with its  CSS style features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; An image editing program like Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://csslint.net/"&gt;CSS Lint&lt;/a&gt; – never ever, ever, ever try to implement any CSS without first validating it. CSS Lint provides a really handy CSS debugger where you can copy+paste your CSS code and check for any errors. A single CSS error may be the reason why your CSS style is completely messed up. I use CSS Lint for validation and Chrome’s debugger for element inspection and in case you wonder why I use a second debugger for CSS is because I find CSS Lint more handy for CSS validation purposes  only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with all these in mind / handy, you’re ready for the next stage...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;How to mess with AC’s Widgets and add your own custom styling?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of writing a general strategy, it is best to proceed with a &amp;quot;per case&amp;quot; scenario. &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/v/9bJSG-ETZvs?autoplay=1&amp;hd=1&amp;fs=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;rel=0&amp;" class="fancybox fancybox.iframe"&gt; So I made a video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(please bear with the hybrid language that I speak on the tutorial. It is known as Greeklish ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be adding more video tutorials when I have more time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Get more out of the Developer Portal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2012/12/get-more-out-of-the-developer-portal/"/>
    <id>/blog/2012/12/get-more-out-of-the-developer-portal/</id>
    <published>2012-12-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As much as we all hate bugs and problems, they happen, and it&amp;#39;s also nice to see a lot of you reporting problems in our &lt;a href="http://portal.applicationcraft.com" target="_blank"&gt;Developer Portal&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;#39;d throw out a few tips to help you out, and explain the basics of what we do with your tickets. We&amp;#39;ve already made a few tweaks from comments that have been made, so if you have any thoughts/ideas don&amp;#39;t be shy - we&amp;#39;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As much as we all hate bugs and problems, they happen, and it&amp;#39;s also nice to see a lot of you reporting problems in our &lt;a href="http://portal.applicationcraft.com" target="_blank"&gt;Developer Portal&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;#39;d throw out a few tips to help you out, and explain the basics of what we do with your tickets. We&amp;#39;ve already made a few tweaks from comments that have been made, so if you have any thoughts/ideas don&amp;#39;t be shy - we&amp;#39;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Raising a problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete all the fields! Not only the platform (eg iOS/Android) but also what OS is involved. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attach an app which we can import into our test accounts and quickly and easily recreate the problem. Don&amp;#39;t forget to also include a &amp;#39;step by step&amp;#39; of what to do in your app so we know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example or test app is even better. An export of your app (the .acft file) is preferred and not a download (.zip file) or compiled package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can&amp;#39;t export your app then show us the problem in a video. The old adage: &amp;#39;A picture is worth a thousand words&amp;#39; really is true. Screen shots can also be helpful. It may seem counter intuitive but even if your problem is only experienced on a mobile device, and you can&amp;#39;t easily video that, being able to walk through how to recreate the problem from the desktop app to show the steps can be a lot easier than trying to write it down step by step. &lt;a href="http://www.techsmith.com/jing" target="_blank"&gt;Jing&lt;/a&gt; is very good for doing this. Give it a go next time you have a problem, and simply post the link to the screencast in your ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can do the above it will help speed up the time it takes us to recreate the problem and get it fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;What have we released and when?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve added in a new field to the ticket &lt;em&gt;Planned for Ver&lt;/em&gt; that is being set with the version we plan to release the fix for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve set up some &lt;strong&gt;Custom Queries&lt;/strong&gt; that you can use to see what was released in past versions. As we release new updates I&amp;#39;ll create new queries as we do  (eg 1.28.1, 1.28.2) and as we release a new version (eg 1.29, 1.30). I will then combine all the updates into one query (eg 1.26.x, 1.27.x).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Custom Queries" alt="Send" src="/img/blog/queries-499c6b7b.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set up your own queries on demand but if you have ones that you would like to be publically available, let me know and I&amp;#39;ll sort something out for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Ticket Status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a new issue is raised, it is given the status of &amp;#39;New&amp;#39;. But what happens next and when are you then able to test/check that we&amp;#39;ve sorted out the problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can test the fix when the status changes to &lt;em&gt;Deployed/Released&lt;/em&gt; as that is when the fix is released.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Ticket Workflow" alt="Send" src="/img/blog/ticketwf-70cf1501.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between these 2 steps, there are a number of process steps. If your explanation isn&amp;#39;t clear we may get back to you changing the status to &lt;em&gt;To Clarify&lt;/em&gt;, but in most cases (and especially if you include an example app) the next step would be to set the status to &lt;em&gt;Acknowledged&lt;/em&gt; for the developers to pick up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch out for the change to the &lt;em&gt;Planned for Ver&lt;/em&gt; flag to indicate what version this is due to be released in. This will be done when our QA team have tested internally and passed it as OK to release. In most cases this will be the next release we make, but if there are other things we need to do (update the docs for example), it may be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Keep it Clean&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have confirmed all is OK, please add a comment to the ticket to let us know and we can then close it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;Private Posts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you raised your ticket as a Private post (ie includes information you would not want to have in the public domain, export of an app, screen shots, etc.), we would like to make these Public when they have been closed, so others can also see if they have or had a similar problem.  Please delete any attachments/comments that you wanted private and then un-check the private flag as you confirm back all is Ok for us to close the ticket and the rest of the community can then see what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Release: jQuery Mobile 1.2, Mobile Debugger</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2012/12/release-jquery-mobile/"/>
    <id>/blog/2012/12/release-jquery-mobile/</id>
    <published>2012-12-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last Friday we shipped quite a large new release which I think is worth mentioning. As well as some significant bugs being squashed, we upgraded jQuery Mobile and jQuery UI, and integrated the Weinre Mobile Debugger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;jQuery Mobile and UI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jQuery Mobile is one of the core parts of AC, and every single app uses at least some part of the open source framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last Friday we shipped quite a large new release which I think is worth mentioning. As well as some significant bugs being squashed, we upgraded jQuery Mobile and jQuery UI, and integrated the Weinre Mobile Debugger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;jQuery Mobile and UI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jQuery Mobile is one of the core parts of AC, and every single app uses at least some part of the open source framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in October, the team behind jQuery &lt;a href="http://jquerymobile.com/blog/2012/10/02/announcing-jquery-mobile-1-2-0-final/"&gt;released a major new version; 1.2.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release brings a new popup widget, an autodivider and collapsible option for listviews, and over 100 enhancements and fixes throughout the library to make things smoother, faster, and more polished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://jquerymobile.com/blog/2012/10/02/announcing-jquery-mobile-1-2-0-final/"&gt;Check out the blog post&lt;/a&gt; for a run down of what&amp;#39;s new in jQuery Mobile 1.2.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest version of AC now includes this latest and greatest version of jQuery, and also because of it&amp;#39;s reliance on jQuery UI, we&amp;#39;ve included the latest version of that into this release too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is anything new in jQuery Mobile 1.2 that you would like to see in AC, such as any new or improved widgets, please post in the &lt;a href="http://getsatisfaction.com/application_craft"&gt;forums&lt;/a&gt; and ask others to comment. If we see demand for a feature we will try our best to implement it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Mobile Debugging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also shipped a new feature to allow you to debug your apps right within the devices you are developing for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weinre (Pronounced like the word &amp;quot;winery&amp;quot;) is a debugger for web pages, like FireBug (for FireFox) and Web Inspector (for WebKit-based browsers), except it&amp;#39;s designed to work remotely, and in particular, to allow you debug web pages on a mobile device such as a phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Weinre Debugging" src="/img/blog/weinre-55f96c1d.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AC Weinre Debugging server lets you use the familiar webkit developer tools to debug your mobile web apps, and is yet another way that we are making it easier to build apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check it out at &lt;a href="http://mobile-build-debug.applicationcraft.com/"&gt;http://mobile-build-debug.applicationcraft.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
