<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Application Craft</title>
  <subtitle>A Blog written by Application Craft - the Visual IDE people</subtitle>
  <id>http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://www.applicationcraft.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-04-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Application Craft</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Words from expressFlow CEO Martin Vasko</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/04/expressflow/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/04/expressflow/</id>
    <published>2013-04-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve partnered up with &lt;a href="http://expressflow.com/"&gt;expressFlow&lt;/a&gt;, a small startup providing simple and intuitive document-encryption in the cloud. expressFlow launched an app challenge, which we announced a couple of weeks ago and we caught up with CEO Martin Vasko to get an inside scoop on expressFlow and how the idea of the app challenge was born.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve partnered up with &lt;a href="http://expressflow.com/"&gt;expressFlow&lt;/a&gt;, a small startup providing simple and intuitive document-encryption in the cloud. expressFlow launched an app challenge, which we announced a couple of weeks ago and we caught up with CEO Martin Vasko to get an inside scoop on expressFlow and how the idea of the app challenge was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;expressFlow App Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As developers, we love when things are easy and they just work. Both things were not the case when we began to work with encryption. It was complicated to get things done - even in prototypes. And for a developer everything starts as a prototype. After many of our friends and colleagues experienced the same challenges we thought: Hey, why don’t provide the encryption functionality as an API? No sooner said than done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as some of our friends and customers began to play around with our API and integrated it in different scenarios we previously did not even think about we began to realize: Encrypting files in the Cloud is a very generic use case. Let&amp;#39;s make an app challenge!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But why did we come up with such a crazy idea?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well - we think that encrypting documents is a key requirement for most of the document management systems around. And with the growing popularity of cloud storage providers like Dropbox, Google Drive, Box and others we thought: Well - let’s take the API to another level and let our users and developers show us, what they can imagine with encryption. What about sharing documents from a mobile phone securely in the cloud? How about a nice small app to enable a secure four-eyes-principle? Just to give you a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cloud and mobile - a perfect match?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Cloud and mobile brings me to our partnership: Application Craft shares with us the passion to make development less painful. Their app development platform is designed to reduce the complexity of app development - and they do extremely well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application Craft enables developers to build their mobile app by simply dragging widgets in the browser to assemble a professional mobile app for all major platforms. This approach significantly reduces the complexity of app development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this development platform and by the use of the expressFlow API it should be an easy task to build the next cool mobile secure document sharing app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now we give our developers the opportunity to show us! Accept the challenge and build the next big thing! With the Application Craft platform and the expressFlow API this has never been easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks very much for your time, Martin. And... challenge accepted! If you are interested in participating please see details &lt;a href="http://www.expressflow.com/community/appChallenge2013.jsp"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="AppChallenge" alt="AppChallenge" src="/img/blog/app-challenge-badge-8d860ece.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Application Craft Team&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AC Education - the Students Experience</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/04/ac-education-student-experience/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/04/ac-education-student-experience/</id>
    <published>2013-04-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.creighton.edu/"&gt;Creighton University&lt;/a&gt; recently held an App Dev Argy-Bargy, a competition that was a huge success and attended by many students, IT companies and the press. We caught up with Cindy Corritore, a Professor of IT at the University, earlier this year and heard about &lt;a href="/blog/2013/02/ac-education-creighton-university-experience/"&gt;her experience&lt;/a&gt; from the teaching side. Now we&amp;#39;ve been fortunate to catch up with one of the students and competition&amp;#39;s runner-ups, Morgan McVay, who created the &lt;a href="http://creighton.applicationcraft.com/live.php?formId=c68f1542-8200-4a2f-ad89-79978ecedee7#/c68f1542-8200-4a2f-ad89-79978ecedee7/homepage"&gt;CitySlicker&lt;/a&gt; app with team mate Catherine Lucas . The duo won themselves a Google Nexus 7 tablet in the process and have memories to last a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.creighton.edu/"&gt;Creighton University&lt;/a&gt; recently held an App Dev Argy-Bargy, a competition that was a huge success and attended by many students, IT companies and the press. We caught up with Cindy Corritore, a Professor of IT at the University, earlier this year and heard about &lt;a href="/blog/2013/02/ac-education-creighton-university-experience/"&gt;her experience&lt;/a&gt; from the teaching side. Now we&amp;#39;ve been fortunate to catch up with one of the students and competition&amp;#39;s runner-ups, Morgan McVay, who created the &lt;a href="http://creighton.applicationcraft.com/live.php?formId=c68f1542-8200-4a2f-ad89-79978ecedee7#/c68f1542-8200-4a2f-ad89-79978ecedee7/homepage"&gt;CitySlicker&lt;/a&gt; app with team mate Catherine Lucas . The duo won themselves a Google Nexus 7 tablet in the process and have memories to last a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="toc_0"&gt;Introducing...&lt;strong&gt;Morgan McVay&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id="toc_1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Give us an inside scoop - tell us about yourself!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently am a Junior at Creighton University in Omaha, Nebraska pursuing a degree in Marketing and Economics with a focus in Psychology. I have always been interested in consumer behavior and human choices which naturally involves the reasoning behind using certain websites and apps. This concept immediately prompted my interest in gaining a background in website and app development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first applied for Creighton’s BIA (Business Intelligence and Analytics) course, I only had a general outline of basic development skills (You could call me a master at the monochromatic, Times New Roman generic websites). However, the opportunity to learn how to further broaden my education as well as create a prototype to a phone app was too tempting to pass up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="toc_2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;How did you find working with Application Craft?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience with Application Craft was an enjoyable process! For a beginner like myself, it was a pleasant surprise to discover how clean and seamless AC was to use. I found it incredibly easy to understand and use; it became a vital learning tool throughout the semester. The multitude of video tutorials were one of my favorite features to AC; they were straight-forward, informational and thorough.  However, the unique feature that really sets Application Craft apart from the rest is the reliability and helpfulness of the online community. This forum section became an invaluable resource to me and my partner as we worked our way through to create a fully functioning prototype three weeks later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="toc_3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;And on to the good stuff - tell us about the app you helped to create&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an individual looking to pursue a career in marketing, the first question I asked myself was ‘What app would my peers want to use tomorrow?’ I needed a concept that was simple enough to execute within our time constraint but held enough elegance and complexity to be captivating and desirable. From there my partner and I decided that college students would appreciate the opportunity to see their financial shopping mistakes before they made them and thus CitySlicker was born. Living in a larger city is not the cheapest lifestyle, so we created an app that allows you to track your total as you shop while categorizing your purchases. These categorized purchases then would input into a Zing chart and show the buyer in which area they were spending the majority of their money. This app provides a more visual approach to allow college students the ability to readjust their financial habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="CitySlicker" alt="CitySlicker" src="/img/blog/cityslicker1-4eca0ffa.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before presenting our app during the Argy-Bargy competition at Creighton, we first sent out a survey to a small sample of Creighton students. Of this survey, 90% said they would download CitySlicker if it were available on the market. Their favorite features of the app included the barcode scanner and the clean sleek design.  Introducing the app even prompted future demands to improve the app including a customizable list, online account, and the ability to compare store prices to find deals and coupons. The entire experience was incredibly inspiring and motivating for a young professional like myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="toc_4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are your next steps?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although my formal BIA studies have come to an end, I know the experience and tools that I have collected through Application Craft will be greatly beneficial in my future endeavors. I would recommend Application Craft for any individual who is interested in creating their own app or to those who simply would like to better understand and appreciate the hard work and dedication that go into a creating a fully functioning and sophisticated app. In summary, Application Craft is an invaluable resource for any level of developer and is a worthy investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="toc_5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks so much for sharing with us, Morgan. We wish you all the best in the future!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The Application Craft team&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Collaboration is BIG!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/02/collaboration-is-big/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/02/collaboration-is-big/</id>
    <published>2013-02-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you should already know by now, we&amp;#39;re working on &lt;a href="/blog/2013/01/something-big-is-coming/"&gt;something BIG!&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s an all new cloud based software development platform. And it will be the very first cloud based IDE that every developer will love to use, day in and day out. Please &lt;a href="http://crafted.applicationcraft.com/"&gt;register your interest&lt;/a&gt; and we&amp;#39;ll let you in on the first public beta.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you should already know by now, we&amp;#39;re working on &lt;a href="/blog/2013/01/something-big-is-coming/"&gt;something BIG!&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s an all new cloud based software development platform. And it will be the very first cloud based IDE that every developer will love to use, day in and day out. Please &lt;a href="http://crafted.applicationcraft.com/"&gt;register your interest&lt;/a&gt; and we&amp;#39;ll let you in on the first public beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We live not in a passive society, a read-only society, but in a writable society.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is the very first thing we thought about when we first sat down to plan the next major version of Application Craft, and has continued to be at the very heart of almost everything we are building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is arguably the single biggest advantage when using software in the browser, because the browser is constantly connected via the internet, and because the browser is now the most used application on almost any device. Collaboration is also hugely important when writing software and especially when building for the web. It empowers us to do more, while remaining in the [virtual] company of our friends and colleague&amp;#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of collaborating between you and others when using the browser and the internet are zero. Email, Twitter, Skype - these are all free to use, and they are all about collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It is the long history of humankind (and animal kind, too) those who learned to collaborate and improvise most effectively have prevailed.&amp;quot; - Charles Darwin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, but now I hear a few of you asking the question &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;what if I don&amp;#39;t have anyone to collaborate with?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;. The answer to that is easy and simple... &lt;strong&gt;you do!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is full of like-minded people just like you. People who love building web apps, designing web sites, or creating mobile applications. And they all have something to share, even you! And whether you realise it or not, you co-ordinate and collaborate every single day, with people you have never met or spoken to before. No matter what accomplishments you make, somebody helped you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The largest sites are essentially all about encouraging collaboration and making it easier for us to co-ordinate with each other. Sites and apps like Facebook, Twitter, Gmail, Wikipedia, Github, Basecamp, and now Application Craft are leading the way here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; powerful, and we think you&amp;#39;re going to love what you will be able to do with &lt;a href="http://crafted.applicationcraft.com/"&gt;what we have planned&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AC Education - the Creighton University Experience</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/02/ac-education-creighton-university-experience/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/02/ac-education-creighton-university-experience/</id>
    <published>2013-02-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-02-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Introducing Creighton University&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like to round up different perspectives of various Application Craft users and were pleased when Dr. Cindy Corritore, a Professor of IT in the &lt;a href="http://business.creighton.edu/"&gt;College of Business at Creighton University&lt;/a&gt;, offered her insights on what it has been like to teach with Application Craft.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Introducing Creighton University&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like to round up different perspectives of various Application Craft users and were pleased when Dr. Cindy Corritore, a Professor of IT in the &lt;a href="http://business.creighton.edu/"&gt;College of Business at Creighton University&lt;/a&gt;, offered her insights on what it has been like to teach with Application Craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Teaching mobile app development with Application Craft&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been teaching for about 25 years, and hold a Ph.D. in Computer Science (which I have also taught). My programming is rusty, and I was never a crack programmer. I am more interested in HCI (human-computer interaction, UX). I want to tell you a bit about how I used Application Craft (AC) in a new undergraduate course – with great success, I might add. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever tried to teach programming to business IT students you know the challenge I faced. While some IT students love to program, most do not. In fact, it appears that they have heard horrible things about programming since birth, and have to date successfully avoided it. I was tasked with developing a course that would teach them about programming. The goals for the course were not to develop programmers – but to teach students the language of the world of programming, the inherent difficulties with programming projects, and what it really took to put together something reasonable. I decided to use a hands-on approach, and to focus on apps. I thought students would be excited about developing apps – the cool factor. I searched for a long time for an appropriate IDE – and luckily found the perfect tool, Application Craft. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application Craft was perfect for several reasons. First, it was an online IDE – so it was platform-independent, both for development and for final device deployment. Second, it was developed for teams – and a class fits that description perfectly. Third, it was a real-world tool. That meant you could do meaningful and significant projects with it, the students could put it on their resumes, they could take it with them into business when they graduated, and companies would be interested in it and the students’ work with it. AC could also be used at different levels. For students who wanted to develop very complex apps, AC was more than up to the task. However, it was also the perfect IDE for students who needed to work at a more basic level, yet produce something that ‘worked’. Finally, the creators of AC had developed an extensive set of tutorial videos, user manuals, and an active forum to bring myself as well as my students up to speed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my point of view, the best thing about AC was the ability to develop at a high level using widgets and properties as well as to interact directly with the code. This is the perfect learning environment as you can start high-level to build confidence, then dive into the code when students want to do more with their apps. It was also very easy for me to help them, as I could access their apps in our shared team account. Yet their work was not accessible by other students. I plan to use AC for this course in the future. I hope to add features to the course such as using databases and custom widgets as soon as I learn it. AC is a great product, one of a kind, and I see it as a professional, commercial tool that can also double in education. I can’t say enough good things about it, but am so happy that we were able to use it in the course. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, the students loved AC. They said it was the best part of the course. They took to it quickly and became very good at developing with it within a couple of weeks. This was true of students who did love to program, and of those who did not. It taught them to program just enough for me, let them experience the programs of development such as project management, deadlines, having ideas that then had to be implemented with code, and most of all, team work. One student, Mike Wieger, described it well in his &lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/b2nsn7d"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Argy Bargy Event&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work of the students was so good that we decided to have a competition, with awards for the team built the ‘best’ apps. Our “2013 App Dev Argy-Bargy” was a huge success – it was attended by other students, folks from IT companies around the city, and the press. The top two teams won iPads and Google Nexus tablets, sponsored by businesses, including AC. It was an exciting event, with judges and audience voting via SMS. My favorite part? When a student said, in response to a question, that “we used an IDE called Application Craft, which is platform-independent, device-agnostic, had a great API, and allows for native implementation on devices.&amp;quot; Huh – three months ago these students wouldn’t have known the difference between IDE and API – that is, IMHO. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Argy Bargy Event" alt="Argy Bargy Event" src="/img/blog/argybargy-e9b93f19.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img title="Argy Bargy Event" alt="Argy Bargy Event" src="/img/blog/argybargy2-e513bf61.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img title="Argy Bargy Event" alt="Argy Bargy Event" src="/img/blog/argybargy3-6da6399e.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The State of the IDE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/01/state-of-the-ide/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/01/state-of-the-ide/</id>
    <published>2013-01-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-01-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while ago I wrote about &lt;a href="/blog/2012/10/worlds-first-full-featured-ide/"&gt;what an IDE really is&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, we&amp;#39;ve been thinking hard and working even harder to realise that dream of a real IDE in the browser, and one that can go head to head with any desktop IDE. This is not without its challenges, so I wanted to write a little about how we are tackling these challenges head on, and to reveal a little more about something BIG that we announced &lt;a href="/blog/2013/01/something-big-is-coming/"&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while ago I wrote about &lt;a href="/blog/2012/10/worlds-first-full-featured-ide/"&gt;what an IDE really is&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, we&amp;#39;ve been thinking hard and working even harder to realise that dream of a real IDE in the browser, and one that can go head to head with any desktop IDE. This is not without its challenges, so I wanted to write a little about how we are tackling these challenges head on, and to reveal a little more about something BIG that we announced &lt;a href="/blog/2013/01/something-big-is-coming/"&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;From the Desktop...&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets start by talking a little bit about the current state of the IDE landscape, which, to be honest is pretty bleak. On the desktop, the space is dominated by the likes of Adobe&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.adobe.com/dreamweaver"&gt;Dreamweaver&lt;/a&gt; and the open source &lt;a href="http://www.eclipse.org/"&gt;Eclipse IDE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dreamweaver is traditionally the kind of tool that new, fresh faced developers start with. I remember it was the IDE that I used to build my very first website back in 1998, and I also remember the god-awful and monstrous HTML markup it produced when publishing or exporting your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dreamweaver has moved on greatly since then (it has had to) and now outputs shiny clean markup. It&amp;#39;s support for web standards has also greatly improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dreamweaver has a large community around it, which has helped to create its large library of widgets, making it easy to add commonly used components into your pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eclipse is an altogether different beast, which is due largely to it being an open source project. This means it has a huge community of users and developers building in and on it. Whatever you are building, you can be sure that there is an Eclipse plugin that will help you out with your task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Eclipse can be very heavy at times, and is certainly not very friendly for those of you who are new to the IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest advantage to Eclipse and almost all IDE&amp;#39;s lies in its extensibility. The ability for any developer to extend and customise his/her tools is extremely powerful and very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;To the Browser...&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desktop will always be with us, but like any platform, it has its limitations and its traditions. All of which can be very hard to counter. The desktop is also much slower to react to the changing pace of development and technology. The browser however, is an open door, and moves extremely fast when it comes to embracing the latest and greatest, which means it is now possible to emulate the power of the desktop right within your browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The browser is deeply embedded into our digital lives and is the most used desktop application by far. So it stands to reason that we are seeing more and more desktop applications now moving into the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IDE is no exception. However, no-one has yet managed to replicate the good parts of the desktop IDE&amp;#39;s in the browser. Well... that is until &lt;a href="http://crafted.applicationcraft.com/"&gt;now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;It&amp;#39;s a Big Task, but someone has to do it!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Something BIG is coming! &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://crafted.applicationcraft.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Find out more...&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" alt="Something BIG!" src="/img/blog/something-big-053c1ff0.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re building an IDE that any type of developer will love to use on a day-to-day basis. A code editor that has all the functionality of the best desktop editors, including code-completion, split-panes and live preview. A development environment that can compete with the best desktop IDE&amp;#39;s, and support the basics, along with the most advanced features, such as source control, debugging, compilation/building, and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we&amp;#39;re adding a layer of convenience on top of all this, that will use the expertise that we have built into the current version of AC, empowering novices and the less technical of you to build web and mobile apps extremely fast. Including a widget library that you can use with a simple and drag and drop, and a pixel perfect layout manager to allow you to design your app in an extremely easy way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we are making sure that you can work the way you want to work, which means building an IDE that is extendable and flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any of this has your juices flowing, then we want you to &lt;a href="http://crafted.applicationcraft.com/"&gt;join in the fun&lt;/a&gt;. Something big is coming...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Something BIG is coming!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013/01/something-big-is-coming/"/>
    <id>/blog/2013/01/something-big-is-coming/</id>
    <published>2013-01-25T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-01-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Think the CIA and MI5 is full of secrets? You ain&amp;#39;t seen nothin&amp;#39; yet! These last few months have been very exciting here at AC&amp;#39;s Evil Lair. We&amp;#39;ve been planning and building something that we think will blow you all away, and it&amp;#39;s coming very soon. The next few months will be even more exciting, and we think you are going to love it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Think the CIA and MI5 is full of secrets? You ain&amp;#39;t seen nothin&amp;#39; yet! These last few months have been very exciting here at AC&amp;#39;s Evil Lair. We&amp;#39;ve been planning and building something that we think will blow you all away, and it&amp;#39;s coming very soon. The next few months will be even more exciting, and we think you are going to love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But unlike the secret service, we&amp;#39;re going to show you our secrets, a little bit at a time. If you want a sneak peak, and possibly even have a little play, &lt;a href="http://crafted.applicationcraft.com/"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. Watch this space as we unveil our secrets, one layer at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Something BIG is coming! &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://crafted.applicationcraft.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Find out more...&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" alt="Something BIG!" src="/img/blog/something-big-053c1ff0.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
